<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>King William's welcome; or, A congratulatory poem on His Majesty's happy arriva[l.] Together with the mutual comfort of King and subject, which is fully demonstrated the wise proceedings of the present Parlaiment in suppressing vice, associating and uniting the hearts of His Majesty's subjects. by W.L. Chaplain to one of His Majesty's ships.</title>
            <author>W. L.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 6KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B25574</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99888264</idno>
  <idno type="VID">201069</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240896417</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing L89A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide C.121.g.9[92]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R229239</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99888264</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99888264e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B25574)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 201069)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; A8:1[94])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>King William's welcome; or, A congratulatory poem on His Majesty's happy arriva[l.] Together with the mutual comfort of King and subject, which is fully demonstrated the wise proceedings of the present Parlaiment in suppressing vice, associating and uniting the hearts of His Majesty's subjects. by W.L. Chaplain to one of His Majesty's ships.</title>
                  <author>W. L.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed and sold by J. Bradford, in New-street, without Bishopsgate, near Hand Ally,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London, :</pubPlace>
                  <date>[1692]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Date of publication from Wing CD-ROM, 1996.</note>
                  <note>Two columns of text, initial.</note>
                  <note>First line: "Welcome great prince, thrice welcome let it be."</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="personal_name">William --  III, --  King of England, 1650-1702. --  Poetry --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  History --  William and Mary, 1689-1702 --  Poetry --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-10 </date>
            <label>Simon Charles </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-10 </date>
            <label>Simon Charles</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="ballad">
            <pb facs="tcp:201069:1"/>
            <head>King William's Welcome; Or a Congratulatory POEM on His Majesty's Happy Arriva<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>▪ TOGETHER WITH The Mutual Comfort of King and Subject, which is fully demonstrated <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> the wise proceedings of the present Parliament in suppressing Vice, associating and uniting the Hearts of His Majesty's Subjects.</head>
            <byline>By <hi>W. L.</hi> Chaplain to one of His Majesty's Ships.</byline>
            <lg>
               <l>WElcome Great Prince, thrice welcome let it be,</l>
               <l>Till multiply'd to an Infinity.</l>
               <l>Awake loud Fame, convey it with all speed</l>
               <l>To <hi>Thames,</hi> to <hi>Humber</hi> and to th' utmost <hi>Tweed.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Tell them kind <hi>Neptune</hi> doth at length restore,</l>
               <l>This noble Trust to the triumphing Shore.</l>
               <l>Let the strong Currents of their Tydes transgress</l>
               <l>The bounding Shore, while they their Joy express.</l>
               <l>Let Neighbouring Coasts joyn in the Harmoney,</l>
               <l>Till our rejoycing universal be.</l>
               <l>This tribute he most justly from us claims,</l>
               <l>Since he our freedom gen'rously maintains,</l>
               <l>And Yearly doth his precious Life Expose,</l>
               <l>To boistrous Seas, and the more savage Foes;</l>
               <l>His brave Attempts throughout the World renown'd,</l>
               <l>With bless'd success have ever yet him Crown'd:</l>
               <l>Just Heav'n assists him in a Cause most right,</l>
               <l>And him emboldens valiently to fight</l>
               <l>'Gainst an Usurping and Tyrannick Power,</l>
               <l>Which he resists and lessens ev'ry hour.</l>
               <l>In vain they shatterd Towns re-edifi,</l>
               <l>And make their Castles with <hi>Parnassus</hi> Vie.</l>
               <l>Tho' lofty, they submissively must bend</l>
               <l>Their stubborn Heads, and be at his command.</l>
               <l>Valour and Conduct will at once conspire,</l>
               <l>By Bombs to make their Fun'ral Piles in Fire.</l>
               <l>So <hi>Calais,</hi> tho' tis thought impregnable,</l>
               <l>Was almost by him made irreparable.</l>
               <l>His Boundless Conquests will extend to thee,</l>
               <l>Proud <hi>Dunkirk</hi> are to their Metropoley.</l>
               <l>'Tis not the <hi>Sultan</hi>'s less unhallow'd Hand,</l>
               <l>Whom the Victorious Emp'rour makes to bend,</l>
               <l>Will them secure. The better <hi>Christian</hi> he,</l>
               <l>Hates their Dishonour and their Treachery,</l>
               <l>What tho' Perfidious One most shamefully</l>
               <l>Hath broke the Bonds of Faith and Amity.</l>
               <l>The Sacred Knot remains inviolable,</l>
               <l>And still will be in spite of him and Hell,</l>
               <l>In which United most inseperably,</l>
               <l>We <hi>Devil, French,</hi> and <hi>Turk,</hi> and <hi>Pope</hi> defy.</l>
               <l>The cringing Monsieur to's dishonour craves</l>
               <l>Peace, so much wish'd for by his wearied Slaves,</l>
               <l>Whilst daring <hi>WILLIAM</hi> Valiantly pursues</l>
               <l>Honour, and all base Proffers he doth refuse,</l>
               <l>Fix'd in his Warlike Resolution, he</l>
               <l>Maintains the Antient <hi>English</hi> bravery.</l>
               <l>Then why should we with needless Fears,</l>
               <l>Our minds disturb our ease and quietness.</l>
               <l>Since he's arriv'd what needs there to compleat</l>
               <l>Our Joys, what can our future Hopes defeat.</l>
               <l>The Faithful and that Wise Septemvirate,</l>
               <l>Fix'd in the highest magnitude of State,</l>
               <l>Like the Seven Stars their borrow'd Light re<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </l>
               <l>To him the Source of Lustre and of Power,</l>
               <l>While roaring Guns his Safe Return descry,</l>
               <l>And like tremendous Thunder rend the Sky</l>
               <l>The joyful Bells do Ring, and an <hi>Hussa</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Doth terminate the happy wish'd-for-Day;</l>
               <l>The Night succeeding, Bonfires all do feed,</l>
               <l>As if a Conflagation should succeed.</l>
               <l>Who but the senseless murmuring <hi>Jacobite,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Is not transported at the Joyful Sight.</l>
               <l>Thy Absence, Noble Prince, tho' well sup<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </l>
               <l>By the Sage <hi>Heptarchs</hi> Prudence, Care and G<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </l>
               <l>Was much deplor'd, on thee our longing Isl<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </l>
               <l>Was fully bent, but now Return'd, doth sm<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </l>
               <l>Not <hi>Phoebus</hi> with his Influential Rays,</l>
               <l>More bounteous Heat or languid Earth disp<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </l>
               <l>At thy Return, approaching Hyneus flies,</l>
               <l>And a perpetual Spring her place supplies.</l>
               <l>Strange Revolution, if one may presage,</l>
               <l>We shall enjoy a second Golden Age.</l>
               <l>Hence all Complaints and needless Jealouses▪</l>
               <l>Which Misers make, the Nations grand Dise<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </l>
               <l>Penurious thoughts shall ne'r our Souls con<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </l>
               <l>No Riches like the Riches of the Mind.</l>
               <l>No grievous Fears our Hearts shall discomp<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </l>
               <l>Nor terrours of our fierce envading Foes,</l>
               <l>If thou espouse our just and righteous Cau<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Go to, Great Sir, thy Senate arise conven<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </l>
               <l>That Loyal Council makes the State serene,</l>
               <l>Consult their Soveraign's Honour, Subjcts e<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </l>
               <l>Establish Peace and lasting Happiness</l>
               <l>By thy Example, and their prudent care,</l>
               <l>Vice is restrain'd, no wicked Men will dare</l>
               <l>With impious and unhallow'd Lips propha<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </l>
               <l>The Great Creator's most adored Name,</l>
               <l>Nor with injurious Hands no more deface</l>
               <l>Thy Image to the Nations disgrace:</l>
               <l>From Hellish Plots thy Person thy'l secure,</l>
               <l>And with untainted Loyalty innure</l>
               <l>Thy Kingdom, whilst associated they</l>
               <l>Do bind themselves and People to obey.</l>
               <l>No sculking Traytors here shall more abid</l>
               <l>Nor stain our Isle with barbarous Regicide</l>
               <l>Just Heaven Protects, and timely will discl<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </l>
               <l>The Hellish Combination of thy Foes.</l>
            </lg>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed and Sold by <hi>J. Bradford,</hi> in <hi>New-street,</hi> without <hi>Bishopsgate,</hi> near <hi>Hand Ally</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>